<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Some reasons for annual Parliaments, in a letter to a friend</title>
            <author>N. N.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 38 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A52894</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N58</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R32968</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12803019</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12803019</idno>
            <idno type="VID">94094</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A52894)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 94094)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1037:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Some reasons for annual Parliaments, in a letter to a friend</title>
                  <author>N. N.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>11 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages cropped, stained, with print showthrough, with loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Signed: N.N.</note>
                  <note>Errata: p. 11</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Rules and practice.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:94094:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Some REASONS for <hi>Annual Parliaments,</hi> in a <hi>Letter</hi> to a Friend.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>I Have received yours, and find that you think that imperfect repreſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations of our Affairs, are the occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion that ſo many in your parts, who wiſh well to the preſent Government, ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect that it is too tottering, and unſteady; but with great grief of mind I muſt aſſure you, that the Thinking Men about this Town, have as melancholly a proſpect, of thoſe Affairs: For ſince we ſee ſo lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle is done for ſo great Taxes, we don't only deplore the ſucceſſes againſt us in <hi>Flanders,</hi> but expect great uneaſineſs at home; and we fear the King is not fallen into right hands, and right meaſures to ſupport his Throne, You know me too tender of the Honour of the preſent Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhment, to imagine I will expoſe the failures of it. But ſince you ſo earneſtly entreat me to offer at ſome Remedies, if I think our Circumſtances require them, I ſhall not deny to ſatisfie ſo good a Friend, in ſo juſt a Requeſt, I think our Caſe calls for ſchemes from every hand. I fear ſome Men about the King have falſe Notions concerning Government it ſelf; and that is an Errour in the firſt Concoction. I will not write too pointedly; but without ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſing any body, am willing as far as the brevity of a Letter will permit, to demon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate, that a Limited is preferable to a Deſpotick Monarchy. I believe it more ſuitable to the ends and deſign of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, more conducive to the ſafety and glory of the Prince, as well as better cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culated for the peace and happineſs of the ſubject. I need not uſe any other Arguments to prove this Aſſertion, than Quotations out of Hiſtory; where we ſhall find, that violent Convulſions, ſudden and bloody Revolutions, deplorable and deſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating Civil Wars, do more frequently attend the Deſpotick, than any other form of Government. The deſire of Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty is born with Mankind, and the love of it ſo deeply ingrafted in our Hearts, that in all Ages, and Nations of the Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe, it hath given plain and evident diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coveries, how impoſſible it is to deſtroy it. The more vigorous the Efforts of Deſpotick Monarchs and Governments have been to efface it, the more frequent and bloody ſacrifices have been offered by the People, for its Eſtabliſhment; and more and ſtranger Inſtances can be given of what is here aſſerted under a Deſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick, than under any other Form of Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment. The frequent Rebellions, and repeated Murders, committed upon the Perſons of the Roman Emperors, after that Government became Abſolute: The de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſing and maſſacring of ſo many of the <hi>Gothiſh</hi> Kings in <hi>Spain</hi> and <hi>Italy;</hi> the innu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merable Inſurrections &amp; bloody Revenges upon the Perſons of their Kings, practiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Subjects of thoſe Deſpotick Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchs in <hi>Aſia</hi> and <hi>Affrick,</hi> in all Ages, and at this day in the Empires of <hi>Turkey,</hi> and <hi>Perſia, Mogul, Fez, Morocco,</hi> and <hi>Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covy,</hi> are plain and evident Proofs, of what is alledged, and may give a juſt diſtaſte to every wiſe and prudent Prince
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:94094:2"/>of a Government, which is always un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the cruel Circumſtances, either of devouring their Subjects, or of being pulled in pieces by them. Whoever will look into the Records of thoſe Countries which I have mentioned, will draw in his own mind too ugly and too ghaſtly an Image of Abſolute Power, to be in love with ſuch an hideous Monſter. I am not willing to tax any man with ſo unnatural a Luſt, but in Policy as well as Religion, Princes and their Miniſters ſhould avoid all appearance of Evil; they ſhould not give the People the leaſt um<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brage to ſuſpect ſo Fatal a Project is hatching againſt their Liberties: Our Government has more than ordinary need to ward off all occaſions of Jealouſie: For however unwilling ſome are to own Election to be King <hi>William</hi>'s Title, I hope no body dares affirm we were Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quered; and I am ſure he has not the Crown by the <hi>Jus Divinum,</hi> right of <hi>Lineſhip;</hi> and if his Title is Election, I am as ſure an elective Government has as much need of the Peoples Love to continue it, as it had at firſt need of their Affections to make it: And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore without all queſtion, a man cannot expreſs his Love to this Government more effectually, than by pointing out what are the true and genuine Methods to conſerve the eſteem of all the honeſt and well-affected Subjects. And two things preſent themſelves to my thoughts, which I humbly recommend to the Conſiderati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the preſent Parliament, His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty, and all the People of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Firſt is Annual Parliaments. I ſuppoſe no body has forgot that at the beginning of the Revolution, in the Act which was made for declaring the Rights of the Subject, after the Grievances reck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned up, it ſays, that for redreſs of all Grievances, &amp; for the amending, ſtrength<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ening and preſerving of the Law, Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ought to be held frequently, which muſt mean frequent Parliaments; and not frequent Seſſions of the ſame Parliament; or our Conſtitution is but little amended by that Act. Our Anceſtors underſtood the neceſſity and wiſdom of having frequent Parliaments, <hi>Alfred</hi> as you may ſee in the <hi>Mirrour of Juſtice,</hi> Chap. 1. Sect. 3. Ordained, That the Parliament ſhould meet every year twice, or oftner if need were. There are many Statutes in <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> the Thirds time, that a Parliament ſhall be held once a year, and oftner if need be. That Act is no leſs than three times reiterated in his Reign. Acts of the ſame import are made in <hi>Richard</hi> the Seconds; and theſe Acts were made when Prorogations, and long Continuances of the ſame Parliaments were not in Uſe. <hi>Henry</hi> Sixths Reign was the firſt in which Prorogations began at all to be made for any time, and they were but very little uſed till <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighths time. But the uſual way formerly was to call a Parliament, at leaſt once a year, and as ſoon as their buſineſs was done, to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve them. They adjourn'd themſelves for ſome ſhort time, but the King did not prorogue at pleaſure. That this was the conſtant practiſe I appeal to the Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament Rolls; but I don't ſo much dote up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Antiquity, as to deſire to revive that practice, unleſs I can prove it reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble and advantagious. I think it is very much ſo in the preſent juncture. It can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be unknown to King <hi>William,</hi> how much he has been Libelled, becauſe ſo many of his Officers are in the Houſe. Thoſe that wiſh him ill, have hit the Blot: But it has diſgraced him with thoſe that wiſh him well. It is fit the King ſhould chooſe whomſoever he thinks
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:94094:2"/>fit to ſerve him in his Imployments; but it will be matter of ſcandal if the People think their repreſentatives are bought off, Whether by Places or Penſions. But if they are choſen Annually, it will not eaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly be believed that an unfair Bargain can be ſtruck with them. Our Taxes will be leſs heavy whilſt we think our Repreſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tative Aſſeſſors pay their Proportion. How juſt the Clamours and Suſpicions of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind are, I don't determine, but I know they are great, and by every body, and every where believed, and that by this courſe they would be avoided; if the Accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſations are well grounded, if Votes are pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſed by Places, or moſt of the Members are more than Ten times Re imburſed their own ſhares of the publick payments; then indeed the ſafety, and very being of the Conſtitution is ſtruck at, our Funda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentals are debauched, Our Houſe of Commons is become a Parliament of <hi>Paris,</hi> to do as the Court would have them: And nothing but what they direct; <hi>Scotch</hi> Lords of the Articles are, as it were, by a Court-Cabal introduced; and Member<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip inſtead of being a Deputation from the People, is become a Preferment for life under the King. But whatever the Malicious ſay, I am not willing to believe theſe things. But I am willing that it ſhould be made apparent for the future in every Parliament, that ſits, That there is no likely-hood that it is Debauched, and that will be made apparent by Annual Parliaments. But to lay aſide the peculi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>arity of our preſent caſe; let me treat of it under a General Conſideration. And I will endeavour to ſhew the Expediency of Annual Parliaments; and that I ſhall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to make good by the nature of Parliaments, and of their Delegations, by which it appears that the Members are Delegated by their Electors, to ſupply their places, in Adviſing, Treating, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſulting, and Determining upon the Great and Important Affairs of the Nation, which appear and are upon the Stage, in that juncture wherein the Parliament is ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moned. When ſuch a Parliament is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued long <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> anſwers the preſent Occaſion for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> were ſummoned, great Inconveniencies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, and unlike<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to follow. A man may be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent me in one juncture, whom I might very reaſonably judge unfit to do <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother. A man may be qualified, to Adviſe, Conſult, and Determine about the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>provement of Trade, and the Manufactures of the Nation; and yet may be unfit to offer Advice in the great Affairs of Peace and War. A man may have know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge enough to act in ſuch matters, who may want integrity, faithfully to repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, and procure redreſs for Grievances, which will be ſpringing up in any Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment. When Parliaments are An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nually choſen, we can chooſe our Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentatives, with an Eye to the preſent Circumſtances of Affairs, and the preſent Exigencies of the Nation: But when the ſame Parliaments are continued upon us, we are put upon the unreaſonable Task of Prophetically chooſing men fit to repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Us amidſt the unforeſeen &amp; unexpect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Accidents, and Affairs which may ſall in, ſo long as the Prince and his Miniſters thinks ſit to continue the Parliament then ſummoned. Beſides, when the buſineſs of the Nation has been, as it were Monopo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lized for many years, then whenſoever we have the Opportunity of Electing a new Parliament, we are put <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> on the ſame neceſſity of chooſing a Kna<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Skil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>n the Rules of the Houſe and Parliamentary Laws, as we are ſometimes in private mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of choſing <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> that is expert in Pleadings, and the methods of the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:94094:3"/>Law, though we are not ſatisfied of his moral honeſty; whereas if every body had their turn, in a little time, all the principal Free-holders would be inſtruct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and directed in the intereſt of their Country.</p>
            <p>Again, delegation imports in its own na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture a power in the perſon, or perſons, who delegate, to revoke it at his or their plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, and can be continued no longer, than during the time, and particular oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions, for which it is granted; and is underſtood to be no longer in being, than the Conſtituents think fit to conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue it. And delegates are always upon their good behaviour. When Parliaments are not Annually choſen, but continued during the Princes pleaſure, longer than the preſent exigency for which they are called, the nature of a delegation, and the undoubted priviledges of thoſe that chuſe them, are quite altered and over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned; and the delegation is perpetua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, though it ſhould appear that the delegates are unfit for it, or unfaithful under it. From delegates whom we our ſelves have impowered, they become ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolute Maſters; or if delegates ſtill, they are transformed from being the peoples delegates and repreſentatives, into the Princes delegates and creatures. By eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry repeated prorogation the peoples Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion is cancell'd, and their new Being is derived from the Prince his will and pleaſure, and meaſured out, and continued, according to their humble complyance with what is demanded from them.</p>
            <p>Again Annual Parliaments are beſt ſuit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to a limited Monarchy, (which I hope all Engliſh-men think the beſt) Annual Parliaments contribute moſt to the Eaſe Safety, and Glory of the Prince, as well as to the Security and Happineſs of the Subject: By Annual Parliaments a Conſidence is begotten betwixt the Prince and the People; the Prince can ſcarce demand that, which the people will refuſe, when the people have a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence in him, and nothing contributes ſo much towards that confidence as Annual Parliaments. I again ſay they remove all the Jealouſies which people retain of hav<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their Repreſentatives debauched, which will be ſuſpected when Parliaments are continued, they are a Curb upon De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigning Miniſters, who for ſelfiſh and fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter ends may be for endeavouring to Embroyl the King and his people, and many times have proved very Uneaſy and Ruinous to Princes. They remove Griev<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances before they get to ſuch an height as to pinch the people ſo hard, as to occaſion ſuch loud and unmannerly Complaints, as have many times obliged Princes from a miſtaken point of Honour to refuſe their Redreſs, and ſo have engaged them in un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neceſſary diſputes with the people, which have leſſened the Figure, Glory and Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wer of ſome of our Princes, both here at Home, and amongſt their Neighbours, more than any other thing in the world. Whereas when a King of <hi>England</hi> does meet his people in Parliaments Annually choſen he may reaſonably expect to find them fraughted with freſh deſires to unite him cloſer with his people, to aſſure him of their confidence, and affection, and to give him earneſt of it, which placeth him in the heighth of power, reputati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and glory. For a King of <hi>England</hi> encircled with a confiding Parliament, is then in his Emperial Luſtre, more abſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lute than any Monarch of the Eaſt, then he infallibly becomes the Terror of his Foes, the ſtay and ſupport of his Friends, &amp; the joy, comfort, and darling of his People.</p>
            <p>As to the People, the continuing of the ſame Parliament, is a more fatal, and
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:94094:3"/>likely to be a more <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> blow up all our Liberties, than either <hi>Quo Warranto's, Regulations,</hi> or any other Methods practiſed in the two laſt Reigns, of which we complained ſo loudly, and with ſo much <hi>Juſtice.</hi> A Prince may more certainly Bribe, than <hi>Quo Warranto</hi> or <hi>Regulate</hi> Parliaments. The Nation will be awakened at thoſe irregular ſteps: But a King may ſeem to proceed accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to Form, when he continues that Parliament which he has made his Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners. King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second was his Arts-Maſter in this point: He was no Enemy to a Long Parliament, whilſt he had a Long Liſt of many of their Names, of whom a certain Great Man can give a good account; but as long as our King employs him, I will not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>decently reap up his faults; though if he can be caught at the ſame Work now he ought to be expoſed.</p>
            <p>It will add Weight to what I have ſaid, if we find it the practice of the greateſt, wiſeſt, and moſt renowned Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, to make proviſion for the Fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quency and Rotation of their Diets and Parliaments. And that the moſt Glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and Victorious Princes in thoſe Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions have met moſt frequently with their People in Parliament. I ſhall not inſtance from our own Hiſtory; I ſuppoſe no En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh Man ignorant how frequently our <hi>Edwards</hi> and <hi>Henries</hi> put a ſtop to the Courſe of their Victories, to meet their people in Parliament. Have not the peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of <hi>Spain</hi> made moſt careful proviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons for the frequent meeting of their States, with ſecurities and cautions pecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liar to themſelves, and much more exact than what other Nations can pretend to, and have not the greateſt and moſt vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctorious of their Kings been the readyeſt to enlarge their Privileges, and moſt ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Charles</hi>'s, were as careful of meeting their people in their Diets, as of ſubduing and conquering their Enemies: And it is ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervable, that King <hi>Charles,</hi> who was moſt exact in meeting his people fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently, raiſed the Monarchy of <hi>Spain</hi> to its higheſt pitch of ſtrength, and glory; and his Son <hi>Philip,</hi> who offered at a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpotick power, and abhorr'd the meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with his people, did firſt ecclypſe the Glory of that Monarchy, and threw it into that decay and conſumption, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der which it laboureth to this day. Did not the <hi>French</hi> Nation upon their Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt of, and Settlement in <hi>Gaul,</hi> now <hi>France,</hi> eſtabliſh the frequent meeting of their States? And the moſt Victorious of their Princes have been moſt exact in meeting of their people, oftener than Annually, as may be inſtanced in their <hi>Clovis,</hi> their <hi>Pepin, Charlemaign,</hi> and the ſucceſſors of <hi>Hugh Capet</hi> for ſeveral Ages. And though <hi>Lewis</hi> the Eleventh, and moſt of his ſucceſſors have endeavoured to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs the States, and rendered that Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchy deſpotick, yet it hath furniſhed ground for ſo many Commotions, Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mults, Leagues and Rebellions, as have not only frequently put a ſtop to the courſe of their Victories, but unravelled all their ſucceſſes; and the ſubjects have many times return'd with intereſt the en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>croachment of their Princes upon their Liberties, and reduced that Monarchy to the laſt gaſp; and the ſtruggles of the people of <hi>France,</hi> and Parliament of <hi>Paris,</hi> during the minority of this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent King, to recover their loſt Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, joyned with many other inſtances which their Hiſtory affords, do plainly demonſtrate the tottering, and dange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous condition of all deſpotick Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments.
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:94094:4"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> calamities was <hi>Germany</hi> expo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to; full of civil Wars and diſcords within, by the Competition of Princes for the Empire; harraſs'd and depopu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lated from without, by the <hi>Hungarians, Slavonians, Vandals,</hi> and <hi>Danes,</hi> to all which no remedy could be found, but by the eſtabliſhment of frequent and An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuals Diets; by the Golden Bull in <hi>Charles</hi> the Fourth's time; wherein the abſent Princes, Imperial Cities, and <hi>Hans Towns</hi> who ſend their deputies, take eſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial care of changing the deputies every Diet, leſt they ſhould be bribed, and gain'd by the Imperial Miniſters. By this wiſe proviſion for frequent Diets, peace was ſettled at home, competition of Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tles for the Imperial Dignity were extin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſhed, Foreign Invaſions repreſſed, and the whole Body preſerved in health and vigour: In a word, their Annual Diets are an invincible Barrier againſt the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>undations of the Turks on the one ſide, and the encroachments of the French on the other. And it is that only which has preſerved them from being ſwallowed up betwixt theſe two troubleſome Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours. I do omit to inſtance from <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Switzerland</hi> and <hi>Poland,</hi> which have hitherto been preſerved invincible, by the frequent Aſſemblies of their States; for ſince the two firſt are Republicks, and the laſt is an elective Monarchy, where the Election proceeds without a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny regard to the Family of the deceaſed King, they may not be thought proper inſtances to be followed in an hereditary Monarchy, (as the True Sons of the Church will call ours) yet there are ſome <hi>Recipe</hi>'s which are good in all Caſes, at all Times, and under all Governments; of which kind I take Annual Parliaments to be one.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> what I have ſaid, has any Weight with the preſent Parliament, we may hope ſhortly to have a New one; and then it will be of great uſefulneſs to ſet down what are the great and indiſpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible Characters, or Qualifications of a Parliament - man; and they are theſe; Senſe, Courage, and Integrity.</p>
            <p>Senſe has divers acceptations; but that ſence that is required to capacitate a Man for ſerving uſefully, within thoſe walls, is not the Learning of Univerſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, but the knowledge of <hi>England.</hi> A Senſe of Liberty, of what is meant by our Rights, and properties A Senſe of our Laws and Intereſt, of the Nature of our Government, Of our Trade, of our natural ſtrength and welfare. It cannot be denyed but that the Comparing of the Hiſtories of other Nations. The reading over the Syſtems of Policy, and the Lives of the Great and Exemplary Patriots of Liberty in all Countrys, mightily enlarge their underſtandings, and adorn the Great ſpeakers in that Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly, but if a Man has not reduced all that to the uſe of this <hi>Iſland,</hi> he has not the ſenſe requiſite for this poſt. If his head is never ſo full of the <hi>Idaea</hi>'s of Forreign Conſtitutions, if he is not wiſe as to our Home matters; If he has Travelled Never ſo far for Experience, If he is a Stranger to the <hi>Iſle</hi> of <hi>Britain,</hi> he may make a Loquacious Polititian, a Florid Orator, a States-man in Specu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, but he will never make a Vene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Member of our Parliament. A man that underſtands but well our En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh Manufactory, the natural products of our Country, the ballance of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizing, what Importations, and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portations are to be prohibited, or en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couraged, what are the Grievances the people complain of, which of them are
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:94094:4"/>reaſonable to be redreſs'd, and what are the proper methods of doing it; he that knows how much we can give; what is fit to be given, and can examin How what we have given is layd out, is more fitly Qualified for our Senate-houſe, than if he could diſcourſe of Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, better than all thoſe learned men, who pretend ſo nicely to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand and diſtinguiſh the ſeveral ſorts: If the Countries and Corporations have any thing particular, in relation to their Counties or Corporations to be repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented, they ought to chooſe one that underſtands the Nature of what they would have repreſented, or that is at leaſt capable of being thoroughly inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted in that matter. But at the ſame time that they chuſe one for their par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular purpoſe, they ought to conſider that he Votes for the whole Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth, and therefore they muſt not chuſe any man that is addicted only to their Intereſt, but ſhould always delibe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate whether he is of publick and uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal ſpirit, as well as a proper Advo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate for them. But this will come in more properly, when I ſpeak concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Integrity.</p>
            <p>The next Qualification is Courage: Although the Word Parliament ſignifies to ſpeak freely the mind, and tho' Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty of Speech is always granted to all Parliaments, yet Courage is neceſſary up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on many accounts; it is often neceſſary to withſtand the Frowns of a Prince, it is neceſſary to bear a man above popu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Clamor, it is neceſſary when Peace and War is debated. There has ſcarce been any Reign wherein the Princes have not Hectored ſome of the Members: There is ſcarce any Seſſions, but Arts are uſed to ſtir up the people againſt their own Intereſt; and if a Parliament Houſe upon the noiſe of a War ſhould be ſeized with a panick fear, the whole Nation would ſoon be diſpirited, ſo that it is neceſſary to have Courage to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve his own Integrity, and to uphold the hearts of thoſe that he Repreſents.</p>
            <p>Again, whoever would diſcharge the Office of a good Senator, muſt have Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grity that is proof againſt Gain, againſt Fear, and Sollicitation. If he can be af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frighted, or bribed, or over-ruled out of his own ſenſe of things, he is not fit for that place. Preferments may be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to, but muſt not change the man: Threats muſt make him more watchful and reſolute, and he muſt be ſure to diſtinguiſh between inſinuation and ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gument. He muſt conſider himſelf as a publick Man; he muſt not know his own intereſt, or the intereſt of the place from whence he comes, when the general good of <hi>England</hi> comes in competion, he muſt conſider himſelf as well, and more the Repreſentative of <hi>England,</hi> than of that County, or Town, for which he ſerves: But when he has conſidered the Natio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Intereſt, then in gratitude and duty he is to conſider the Intereſt of the bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of the Electors, more than his own private Advantage; he is to ſtrip him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf of all Relation, and to be akin to the Common-wealth: His ſoul muſt ſoar up into the exalted height of an Heroi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Vertue, and he is to believe that it is a pleaſurable and noble enjoyment e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to ſacrifice himſelf and all private Conſiderations for his Country; he is to lay aſide all private Capacities, and as it were to tranſmigrate into a publick Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyance and Affinity, <hi>Cum calculis ſuffra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giorum ſumeret magnanimitatem Reipublicae,</hi> as <hi>Demoſthenes</hi> uſed to adviſe the people of <hi>Athens</hi> in great Cauſes of Eſtate: He uſed to adviſe, that when they took in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:94094:5"/>their hands the Balls, whereby to give their Voices (according to the manner then in practice at <hi>Athens</hi>) they ſhould raiſe their thoughts, and lay aſide thoſe Conſiderations, which their private Vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations and Degrees might miniſter and repreſent unto them; and ſhould take upon them cogitations and minds agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to the dignity of the State: And there is good Reaſon for this Advice; for certainly, if a man ſhall be only or chiefly ſenſible of thoſe reſpects which his particular vocation or degree, or the State of the County or Town which ſends him, ſhall ſuggeſt and infuſe into him, and not enter into true and worthy Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderations of Eſtate, he ſhall never be able aright to give or take Counſel in Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentary Affairs, in the buſineſs of the Senate-houſe.</p>
            <p>The Notion of integrity has been too much miſtaken of late; the being of a particular Church, or party, has Chriſten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Men Honeſt, and in this laſt Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment pretending to be for King <hi>Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am</hi> has gained thoſe that Epithet who never underſtood a King as the Father of his Country, who make his Political Capacity above the Laws of Men, if I may not ſay the Laws of God too. In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tegrity in the Monarchy of <hi>England</hi> im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plies more of a National, then ſlaviſh Spirit, more of Common Care, than Perſonal Adoration; And it is ſad to think that any Knave can Redintegrate his Reputation, only by being a Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amite, without being Converted to an Engliſh-Man. Thoſe cannot be thought (let them be as much Williamites as they will) to preſerve the Integrity of a Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament-Man, who change or ſtifle their principles for a place; nor can thoſe be thought fit Members for that Houſe, who either for their pleaſure, or private bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs, neglect coming up to Town, no more than thoſe who have ſo many Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices, that they can ſcarce peep within thoſe doors, or who are ſo lazy and loy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering, that they come not till it is too late to hinder them, and ſo ſuffer the Nation to be circumvented by the Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifices and Tricks of the Court, who al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways ſet them on foot, when the Houſe is empty. I would have my Country<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men beware (if ever they chuſe again) of theſe ſelf-intereſted, and careleſs Men. They ought, now their all is at ſtake, to examine how their Members have be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haved themſelves, and not ſell themſelves and poſterity for a drunken bout. Let them chooſe no MAN that has not Senſe, Courage and Integrity, or that will not receive their inſtructions. There are no Counties, and few Towns, wherein they don't underſtand the Intereſt of their Country enough to give general inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions. Let me recommend thoſe to them I have hinted at in this Paper. Adviſe and order them to learn the Art of Tack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſince we can hope for nothing with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out it. Let them give no Money with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out good Country Bills, Let them give it in many Parcels, and Tack ſomething to each; order them to bring in Bills to regulate the Militia, to encourage the Uſe of Fire locks amongſt the populace; to encreaſe our Navy, to reduce all our part of the War to that Navy; to ſettle ſuch Salleries upon the Judges as may make <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>em impartial, to bring in a Bill for Capital Tryals; but it ought to be a better one than Sir <hi>William Whitlocks,</hi> one more clear and more expertly drawn: And a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove all things order them to bring in a Bill to ſecure Annual Parliaments, and the Elections of Members for the future. Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſe them to Ranſack all our own Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords, and to conſult all the ſeveral Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernments
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:94094:5"/>upon that Head. Chooſe but once wiſe and honeſt brave men, and they will find expedients to avoid the diſputes, and baffle the Arts which have rendered Elections precarious and illegal. They will find Methods to be too hard for Court-tricks, and Spend-thrift Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petitors: Chooſe no Man that is not wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling to be inſtructed, you have a Right to inſtruct them: It was the Cuſtom for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly to inſtruct all the Members; and the nature of the deputation ſhews, that, that Cuſtom was well grounded.</p>
            <p>I come in the next place to conſider of Eſtates as a Qualification, I allow they may be ſome additional ſecurity for Mens good behaviour in the Parliament Houſe; but they are far from being an indiſpenſible Qualification. There have been in all Countries Men that have been indefatigable in their Care, and untainted in their Love of the publick, who have had but very ſmall ſhare in it. I will on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly name <hi>Cincinnatus, Attillius Regulus,</hi> and <hi>Paulus Aemilius,</hi> amongſt the Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans; and <hi>Ariſtides</hi> the juſt, amongſt the <hi>Athenians.</hi> Theſe noble Patriots faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully diſcharged many of the greateſt and moſt honourable Employments of their reſpective Republicks, yet lived and dy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed poor, nor had the incorruptible <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew Marvell</hi> our Country-man a much more plentiful Fortune. Riches were ſo far from recommending Men to Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtracy amongſt the <hi>Lacedemonians,</hi> that by the inſtitutions of <hi>Licurgus,</hi> they were only allowed to uſe Gold and Silver for the Utenſils of a baſer Nature. There was formerly, nay there is a Law to this day, that the Electors ſhould make an Allowance for the expences of Members; and it is likely that in the primitive uſe of Parliaments, greater reſpect was had to their abilities, their ſpirit, and their fidelity, than to their riches. But the manner of Chooſing Parliament men is ſtrangely changed; can it be thought un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>likely, that thoſe who ſpend their For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes to be choſen into the Houſe, ſhould re - imburſe themſelves when they are there? Can it be believed that he that pays for his entrance as much as if it were an Office, does not deſign an Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice to make himſelf whole again? Can it be thought ſuch Men ſhall promote publick Vertues, who are advanced to this ſtation by publick Vices; who are more beholding to their Cups, than their Merits for that Honour? Little do the Country that thus Proſtrate the Nature of our Parliaments, for brimmers of Ale and Wine, think, that thoſe draughts let them in, and give them too juſt a Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle to ſlavery. It is a ſtrange Alteration that our Fore - Fathers ſhould Reward the Men whom they pitched upon for that buſineſs, and that now-a-days we ſpunge upon them. We drink till we have loſt our ſenſes, that we may diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſh which of the Competitors has the greateſt ſhare of reaſoning. This is an open and an avowed debauching of the Inſtitution: It were well there were no more baſe Arts practiſed in this matter. But till bribing and drinking will not ſo ſoon recommend Men, as the Characters that I have named, till the Free-holders of the Counties, and the Inhabitants of Burroughs go once about this buſineſs with ſobriety, and without little ends, and partial inclinations, we ſhall never come to a Reformation. <hi>England</hi> will be without ſecurity, for we cannot fall into a ſolid ſecurity, without a well - choſen Parliament. And we ſhall never chooſe a Parliament as we ſhould do, till the Electors chooſe more from Judgment, than Affection; more from Confidence
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:94094:6"/>in their Worth, than for the Liberality of their Entertainments. Although the Romans allowed the Candidates for any other Office to cajole for Votes, yet it was entirely forbid to all Men that came into the Senate. Nor was drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for Parties any more in uſe when they choſe Senators at <hi>Athens,</hi> or <hi>Sparta,</hi> nay at the General Aſſembly of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-wealths, and States of <hi>Greece</hi> (call<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Council of <hi>Amphictiones</hi>) if any Man had but deſired to be choſen, he for that reaſon loſt his Election. The Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate of <hi>Venice</hi> at this day, to prevent the poſſibility of a Sollicitation upon the part of the Candidates; and to remove all fears, and that no other Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion than the merit of their Candidates may influence the Electors, has conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted the Ballet; and though I don't hope to fee ſo nice a Reformation, yet I may wiſh that ſuch ſcandalous bribing, drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and ſollicitation, as is not any where to be found, either in antient, or modern policy, in the Choyce of thoſe who are the Conſervators of the peoples Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, may be baniſhed likewiſe our Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions. Our Neighbours of <hi>Scotland</hi> might inſtruct us how to chooſe Members, who are ſo far from treating and carouſing, that if it can be proved they ſollicite a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny one Man, it deſtroys their Election. Whilſt ſuch corruptions as are amongſt us laſt, there can come no good; and we muſt degenerate into ſlaves. It is in vain to talk of amendment, or to dream of <hi>Englands</hi> ſecurity, till we chooſe our Parliaments aright; and till thoſe that take leaſt pains and ſpend no mony to be choſen, are ſent thither. Therein does and will conſiſt <hi>Englands</hi> ſecurity: I wiſh to God all Mankind may be ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied that it does ſo, if this Parliament ſhould be diſſolved; which it muſt be, if the people have the ſenſe, honeſty, and courage, to demand in a prudent manner to have it made a Law that we ſhould have Annual Parliaments.</p>
            <p>The abuſes of Elections will be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented by Annual Parliaments, and will by no other Method be prevented ſo cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly. When the Parliaments are cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen Annually, no body will think it worth the trouble and expence of appearing and ſtriving for ſo ſhort-lived an Office and Authority, which will indeed rather be a burdenſome Truſt; ſo that thoſe who have the beſt Reputation with them will be choſen by the people: Nor will men ſacriſice their Credit with the people, either for Ambition or Avarice: If they are ſure to be layd aſide like Almanacks, at the next Annual Election; ſo that the Cure of this evil is a ſtrong argument for what is propoſed, and may ſerve to rouze my Country-men out of that ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pine ſtupidity and ignorance of their own good, into which they ſeem to be ſunk, and which is both the cauſe and effect of Tyranny, and makes us with all our boaſted Rationality worſe than the Oxe or the Aſs, than the Beaſts of burthen; for ſo are Men that don't know and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider.</p>
            <p>When I firſt ſet pen to paper, I in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended to have treated upon a ſecond Head of Diſcourſe, which would have been by way of Prevention and Caution, againſt a project, which will either ſet the whole Nation by the ears, or entayl ſlavery upon us and our Poſterity. The project upon which I intended to have deſcanted, is the general Exciſe; but I have wrote a long Letter already, and the Notion and Tendency of ſuch an Exciſe deſerves a whole Letter apart; when my Affairs give me leiſure to ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tomize it, you may expect to hear of
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:94094:6"/>me at length, I would refer you to ſuch an Opportunity; but ſince I here men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned it, I fear you will think me to blame, if I don't a little, though with never ſo ſhort touches, explain my ſelf upon it; but I will only at preſent give you the Picture in Miniauture of that Exciſe which is already eſtabliſhed; the Never-to-be-forgotten <hi>Marvell,</hi> of whom I juſt now made mention, is the hand that drew it. His Words are theſe:</p>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Exciſe a Monſter, worſe than e're before,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Frighted the Midwife, and the Mother tore.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>A thouſand Hands ſhe has, a thouſand Eyes,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Breakes into Shops, and into Cellars pryes:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>With hundred rows of Teeth the ſhark exceeds,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And on all Trade like</hi> Caſawar <hi>ſhe feeds.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Chops off the piece whereſ'ere ſhe cloſe the Jaw,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Elſe ſwallows all down her indented Maw.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>She ſtalks all day in ſtreets, conceal'd from ſight,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And flys like Bats with leathern wings by Night.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>She waſtes the Country, and on Cities preys.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Her of a female Harpy in Dog-days,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Black B— of all the Earth born race moſt hot,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And moſt rapacious like himſelf begot,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And of his Brat enamour'd as't increas'd,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Bougred in Inceſt with the mungrel Beaſt.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <p>What are my own Thoughts about a general Exciſe you may command, if you think it needful, in the mean time,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>I am, SIR, <hi>Yours Faithfully,</hi> N. N.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="errata">
            <head>ERRATA.</head>
            <p>PAg. 2. Col. 2. Lin. 5. read the ſame Parliament. Ib. l. 9. for altred r. <hi>Alfred.</hi> p. 3. col. 1. l. 9. for Aſſertors r. Aſſeſſors. p. 4. col. 1. l. 10. for convinced r. continued.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
